What do you got,
>> coach? What's up? Uh,
very simply, why do you think that Sam
has been so effective limiting
interceptions since week 11?
>> Um, I think I think what you're looking
at is I don't know if it was just like,
hey, week 11 happened, you know, let's
draw a line in the sand, all of a sudden
we're changing a bunch of stuff. I think
you're looking at the product of, you
know, evolution over the course of this
season of just kind of sticking to our
process and not panicking when things
didn't necessarily go our way and
doubling down on how we want to play
football. But, uh, Sam's been decisive
the whole way and he's done a great job
really in the last whole season, you
know, but, uh, definitely this last
month or so in this final stretch.
>> Drake May has been a leader in the
playoffs for both passing and rushing
statistically. What's the biggest
element as far as making him
uncomfortable?
>> We have to play you have to play great
football. Um they're really good
offense. They're really complimentary.
Um
you know if they if you don't if you if
you don't force them to, they'll run it
every snap, you know. So you got to you
got to be able to control the game and
put it on our terms. And then um the the
thing that makes Drake, you know, so
dangerous in addition to a lot of other
quarterbacks in our league is um in
addition to the arm talent, the
processing and the movement, you know,
he's got a playmaking ability late late
in uh late in plays. So, um, we got to
be relentless in how we play and, um,
we talk about 12 was one with our rush,
but, uh,
I'm sorry, but it threw me off, but, um,
he likes to escape up the middle, so we
got to build the wall, everybody work
together, and play play relentlessly.
Hey coach, uh in week 16 in that
Thursday night game wins the Rams to win
overtime. You elected to play defense
first and that worked out. In this
postseason tournament, we've seen two
ball first teams win. Has that changed
you and your staff's thinking at all in
the least bit?
>> Um you know, we have our philosophy on
how we want to handle overtime. uh
there's some variables that change from
game to game and so we kind of leave
that breathing room for us uh on how we
want to go into game and what what we're
going to like to do and it could it
could change in game on what we want to
do uh for overtime.
>> Mike, what is it about um Sam's mental
makeup that he's able whether early in
his career or even in games when he
might be struggling um that he's able to
withstand that adversity and bounce back
and finish strong and keep fighting?
>> Yeah, Sam Sam's just been so resilient.
I mean, um,
I feel like I'm giving you guys terrible
answers because I'm giving you the same
answer every time, but that's really
what it is. It's just he's so steadfast
in his approach. Um, I think he's
confident in who he is. I think he
understands that how much his team
believes in him and has his back. So,
just keep keep firing away, man. You
know, keep being you. Go to the next
play. He's the same guy after he has a
perfect passer rating and he's not
strutting around like he just, you know,
solved all the world's problems compared
to a game where maybe, you know, we
didn't execute as well as we did. So,
that's what you appreciate about him.
>> Mike, right here in front of you.
>> Thanks.
>> Uh people talk a lot about culture and
NFL teams. What is the tone that you try
to set in your building and how do you
see players latch on to that and reflect
that?
We we we use the term like, hey, this is
how we roll. And we say we want to be
loose and focused. So
everything kind of falls out, you know,
from from that kind of feeling that you
want to that you want to have in our in
our in our building. And a lot of that
is has come from the spirit of our our
team and our organization from uh
throughout the whole history of the
Seahawks, especially from when Pete was
there. And that's something that uh Jody
and John felt strongly about. they want
to carry over into uh into you know our
team and I think that's really cool. You
know our spirit is kind of unique to us
and um you know it's a it's evolved and
changed since since we took over but um
it's still you know rooted in the
foundation of the Seahawks that
everybody is a lot of people are
familiar with. So it's something we're
really proud of.
>> Mike right here um when you were at
Michigan you referenced the Teddy
Roosevelt famous line speak softly and
carry a big stick with your players. Did
you use that at all here in Seattle? And
whether you did or not, do you feel like
this team embodies the spirit of that
quote and why or why not?
>> Well, I haven't I haven't used that um
with our team here, but I I mean that's
that's a quote obviously that resonates
with with me and um obviously not the
most outspoken guy of all time, but you
know, you want your team's tape to
really do the talking and and I think
our guys have done a great job of that.
We've been really poised in these games
and our guys like, you know, they talk
some smacker once in a while as they
should and uh keeps it fun, you know,
like I think the thing that I'm like
proud of is is if you just we just I
just left our defensive team meeting or
even our team meeting, you know, it's
not like this where I'm just like
lecturing on a thing and you guys are
just listening. I mean, it's
interactive. There's music playing. It's
a lot of great energy, a lot of
positivity. Um, you know, guys are
talking crap and we're making it's just
but it's loose and focus to, you know,
to to the question earlier. Um, but then
when it's time to work, there's a
standard that we want to uphold. And,
um, there's different ways to kind of
get that done on a daily basis.
Sometimes it manifests itself a little
bit differently. But, um, I think if you
watch our tape, I think that's pretty
consistent with what President Roosevelt
said.
>> Congrats, coach. Um, last time out
Seahawks Patriots in the Super Bowl, it
was a heartbreaking loss for the
organization. Although there's no
currently active rostered players that
played in that previous Super Bowl
matchup, do you think there's still kind
of a mentality around the team, around
the training facility to kind of avenge
that game for the sake of the
organization?
>> No,
we haven't talked about it once. Um, and
it's not with it's not due to a lack of
respect for for our teams and our
history and what we've done in the past,
but um we're really focused on this
game. like you know it's funny it's like
a meme now but when we when we say it's
about us it really is you you got to
back that up with your actions and
that's how we live it every day and
right now we're focused on how well we
can go get ready to go play this game. a
coach in front of you here on your left.
Um, one more on Sam.
>> We've heard you and a lot of the
teammates say this season. He's got some
stuff about him, stuff being the word
there. Yeah. You know, how much when you
got a guy like that, especially at that
position, how much can the rest of the
team really rally behind that? And we've
certainly seen that kind of manifest
itself, but how much can that really
help your team rally behind this guy?
>> Well, I think that just means that he's
he's a real guy. You he's got real
emotions. He's got real he's got a real
competitive spirit. Um there's things
that piss him off, you know, especially
if things don't really go his way. You
know, we've had some great competitive
battles in practice over training camp
is as I'm listening to your question,
those are the things I'm thinking about
and and frankly that's probably when he
played some of his best football. So, um
he's just real, you know, it's just
that's who he is. If he if he was a
loud, outspoken guy that that's who he
was and our guys would rally about him.
But I think the most important thing is
he's just who he is every day.
>> Standing on your right.
>> Uh hi Mike. When you were considering
signing Demarcus Lawrence last year,
what do you remember about the context
that Adden was able to provide having
worked with him? And how have you seen
that bear out particularly with the way
he's able to defend against the run?
>> It was a no-brainer. I mean, just from
AD being with us the whole season,
understanding how we operated, uh what
type of people we wanted in our
building, and the really our play style.
Um we really felt like that could help
take our defense to the next level. And
man, it's paid incredible dividends. and
and uh I feel like Demarcus would tell
you this, but I feel like we're getting
his best version of himself and uh the
best version of his game as well. So,
it's it's been a win-win.
>> Hello, Insign from TVA. You make the
best game plan for the playoffs. Now,
what is the the biggest challenge to
make the game plan for the against the
Patriots?
>> I think the biggest challenge is we have
too much time. [laughter]
You know, yesterday was a dark day just
kind of going in and out of rabbit holes
and um but I think I think I think the
important part is like how well we can
streamline streamline it for our guys.
Um make sure we're always in our
wheelhouse about what we execute what we
do well and uh when you have extra time
that's hard because you know we're
trying to find solutions and try to find
answers for our guys but sometimes you
just got to shut up and let the guys go
play. coach right here, Buchari for La
Pera. Um, the last five games you've
played, you've had four divisional
matchups and you've played two teams
twice in the last five games. Does do
you think it's a bigger challenge for
you to get back to planning for a team
that you haven't played all season after
weeks where the game plan has been so
focused on teams you know so much?
>> Yeah, it's an interesting question. Uh,
you're right. I mean, when you're
playing teams multiple times, you're
going off of uh a lot of your decision-m
is off how the last game went and how
you anticipate the team reacting and
kind of what you feel like your next
move should be. Uh also the teams that
you're familiar with personnel wise,
things like that. So, the way we treated
this game was just, hey, let's just go
back to square one. Um treat it like we
would any other week like we would
throughout the season and uh and go put
our best foot forward. Now, having the
extra week does help, you know, not not
being as familiar with the Patriots, uh,
as some of the other teams we just
played.
>> Hey, coach, over here on your left, uh,
so you talked about process all year.
Um, and this has got to be a challenge
to the typical process you have. So, now
that you're in it, how have you been
able to uh, you know, stick to that
process and any notes you've already
started to have for yourself for maybe
the next time you get back here?
um what I told our team and look it's
funny you know you're not looking at the
guy that's been to the Super Bowl like
six time you know it's just this is our
all of our kind of first time going
through this experience and I think
that's been an edge for us throughout
the whole season is every time we've
gone into a new experience together uh
we have principles that we want to abide
by and those are kind of like our
guiding lights in terms of how we want
to operate and how we want to make our
decisions um but we also know that we're
kind of going through it together and
we're not afraid to pivot and use
different methods and things like that.
So I think this is an example of that
where you know we or the principle of
the matter is you know we do want to be
um you know adhered to our process the
best we can like today is kind of as
much of a normal Wednesday as we
possibly can make it but with also the
understanding of there are some things
that are going to be different. You got
to be able to be flexible and pliable
and be able to work through those things
and um at some point you're going to get
distracted and that's okay. And look,
we're it's about how how relentless can
we be coming back to back to center back
and you know be in this moment and up to
this point I've really loved how our
team's operated.
>> Coach, what is
>> coach? What has impressed you most about
what Mike Rapel's been able to do with
the Patriots here in his first season?
and and do you see any commonality
between, you know, how he approaches
particularly his connection with with
players and an individuality of those
connections to get the most out of guys?
>> I'm not very familiar with his like
coaching style in his building. Um, I
can tell you this, I I uh you can't help
but respect the the work that they've
done and the team that they've created.
I think the best compliment I can give
is it's very clear that this is a the
vision of how he wants his football team
and uh I think I can say that with
pretty high confidence and they're a
tough team. You can tell they're
connected which probably speaks to his
coaching style. So um you know they
can't we have a lot of respect for how
they operate for coach Frabel. He's done
a tremendous job.
>> Second round. Hey Mike, speaking of
culture and intent, how have you seen
your leadership shown up in the leadup
to to game week?
>> Well, it's, you know, we've guys from
different different experiences. So, you
know, the Cooper Cups, the Ernest Jones
of the Worlds have been here, you know,
they've given their perspective on how
we want to approach the week. They've
been great. You got guys like Leo that,
you know, necessarily haven't. Um, and
they're giving their fresh perspective
as well. But I think again, it's the
same thing. like look, our our young
guys are probably looking to us on how
we're going to handle, you know, our
emotions and handling, you know, media
stuff, things like that. And um we take
it in stride. We're loose and focused
and uh you know, kind of kind of enjoy
the moment, but then, you know, let's
get back to work when we need to.
>> Um yeah, Mike, [clears throat] the
obviously had great success with your
fourman rush on the on the defensive
line this year. How important is what AD
does up there and working with that and
kind of the stunts and and things like
that that he helps deise? whole ad, you
know, he definitely leads the charge
with our front. Uh, Justin Hines, Chris
Partridge are very much a huge part of
that equation as well. Um, I think that
what our coaches do a tremendous job of
is getting the buy in of the guys that
we want to play a certain way and then
and then just injecting a massive amount
of belief to make their best traits come
to life. And it's a great environment
that they've created. the guys have, you
know, they're kind of an embodiment of
the loose and focus where they're, you
know, they're messing around. You know,
the D defensive line rooms are uh are
interesting place, you know, in the NFL
and and we got a great room. They're a
lot of fun to be around, but they they
definitely get after it and they and
they sharpen the rest of the team as
well. I I think you've seen that from
our young offensive linemen as well.
>> Mike, to your left, uh what's how's Sam
progressing with the injury and what's
your sense of how much he'll be able to
do in practice compared to recent weeks?
>> Well, we'll see today. We'll see today.
It's definitely gradually increasing by
the day. So, um, some days more than
others, but, uh, he's in a great spot.
Know he's really confident. Um, we'll
see how today plays out. Not entirely
sure how many throws or what percentage
of throws. I can't really give you right
now.
>> Standing on the right,
>> Mike over here on the wall far right.
There you go.
Now that you're finally back to the
football on the Wednesday, how much is
this going to be a normal Wednesday, a
normal Thursday, or did you even adjust
within that? Are you going to have the
third down's going to be on the same
day? All that or is it what's different?
>> Right. Yeah. Uh it's it's it'll be
consistent like at this point we're in a
normal cadence. Uh couple different
variables in terms of, you know, media
time, uh traveling to a different
location, guys are going to lift after
practice.
outside of that, it's it's uh it's about
as same as as you as you'd like. So, I
think it's uh it's a pretty cool setup
at this point.
>> Looking forward to that.
>> Oh, we're in it right now. This is
great. I'm I'm loving this. This is
awesome.
>> All right. Coach, uh good morning.
>> Good morning.
>> Good morning. Uh after how well Matthew
Stafford played in the last two games
and you guys obviously ended up winning,
does that guy give you guys any more
confidence or even relief going into
another MVP caliber quarterback?
Well, I think what I, you know, what's
one of the special parts about our our
football team is and our players is that
we've been able to win different ways
and and figure things out as games go.
So, uh, that should give us a lot of
confidence going into really any any
type of matchup. Um,
I think it's really that simple. coach
on your right here. There was a moment
in um during the NFC Championship game
in the wake of the uh the Reek Wool and
taunting penalty where it seemed like
Nick Manwari was the voice of reason on
the sideline. Like he's made an an
immediate impact on the field as a
rookie. How impressed have you been with
his maturity off the field and and how
important is is it for you to create a
culture where young players like that
can come in and and be a leader straight
away?
>> Well, Nick's done a tremendous job since
he walked in the door shoot since we
brought him in for for a visit, you
know, pre-draft.
Um, I think what's great about Nick is
in addition, I mean, we all know is you
can see the physical talent, physical
ability, but his eagerness to learn and
the sense of urgency, you know, for
detail and his hunger to like be great,
uh, really stands out. Not a lot of guys
that are that talented really are
interested in doing the amount of work
that actually takes for those traits to
come to life. And Nick Nick does that.
And I think it's not like some secret
thing that he said to the vets, but that
daily approach and mentality that he's
had, I think has earned the respect of
his teammates. And um you got to give
the veterans a ton of credit, too, that
they've they've created an environment
where he can grow and be himself and
have, you know, have moments like that
in a game where um you know, if he if he
feels strongly about something that he
feels empowered that he can say
something and guys will have their back.
And I just think that's been really it's
a tip of the cap to him and and the rest
of the DBs in the room. Hey, hey, Mike,
to your left here, uh, at at this point
in the season, what's the tempo or
intensity you want to see in practice
here the next few days?
>> Uh, it's it's a Wednesday for us, so you
know, we haven't been in pads in two
weeks. We're going to be in pads for the
beginning of practice. It's going to be
great. We won't be in pads the whole
time, and then uh we'll see how the
tempo shakes out. But you're definitely
cutting a few reps here and there, but
uh I think it's important for today and
tomorrow have great practices.
>> Mike, Mike over here, uh, how did You're
right.
>> How did Josh Job go from uh getting his
foot in the door in the practice squad
to being a starter on a Super Bowl team?
>> That's well, it's it's a great example
of how we how you know how we
the pride that we take and how we run
our program where you know when you come
in if you play great football and you're
a great teammate, you're going to get a
you're going to get an opportunity to
play. And Josh was someone that we
acquired at the beginning of last year.
Shout out to our personnel staff for
ideing those type of traits and that
type of personality and the guy just
came in and made a ton of plays on our
ready squad and I remember our veteran
receivers saying, "Hey, like this guy's
pretty dang good." You know, he kept
making plays and when there was an
opportunity for him to get on the field,
we felt really confident for him to go
out there and do his job and he just
kept, you know, just kept hitting it.
Those daily inputs, man, it's it's
powerful when you stack those things.
So, here he is. He should be really
proud of himself.
>> Okay, couple more. Mike,
>> coach, in the back to your right,
>> when you're uh flipping coverages pre-to
post snap, which seems to be an ever
evolving trend in the NFL these days,
how do you do it where you confuse a
quarterback, but you don't confuse your
own defenders, especially against a guy
like Drake May, who's been really good
against disguises this season?
>> Well, Drake Drake has done a tremendous
job. Um,
you know, I think if you're saying if
we're planning on going in there and
fooling them every snap, I think you're
you'd be kidding yourself. uh
our guys have a great grasp of what
we're trying to achieve on every play
and the good news is we know what we're
doing before they snap it. So, we have
that advantage. Uh but, you know,
there's there's weaknesses and strengths
every coverage. There's reasons why
we're calling coverages in certain
situations and I think when you when you
kind of marry those things together and
you stack all those reps over the course
of the the season, uh the guys have a
great grasp of what they're trying to
do. And it's part of our philosophy is
like look when we call certain coverage
we're going to the rules are going to be
the same from you know April 15th to
February whatever it is and that way you
can stack all those reps over the course
of time and get really good.
>> Last question.
>> Being with uh Michael Dixon for two
years now have you gained a greater
appreciation for how a punter can you
know impact and influence a game? Well,
I gota I think um I think Michael's
[snorts] as good as they get right now
in the world. I was also very fortunate
to be around a guy named Sam Cook in in
Baltimore who's a tremendous putter in
his own right. And Sam Sam really opened
my eyes to like what a punter could do
in terms of manipulating the football
and directing it and the different types
of kicks. I mean, he was tremendous and
and um and Michael does he's just right
there with Sam and he's got a great
spirit about him. like it's just uh it's
really he's just a really cool guy, man.
He's just like he's got a great like
he's like he's a competitor but it's the
Australian, you know, twist to it. And
uh great teammate. Guys love him. And I
think you saw from this past game, you
know, he's he's really passionate about
helping putting his his uh his teammates
in position to succeed as well.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you.